repairpal.com 2018-09-21

# Privacy Policy

This privacy policy was last modified on May 17, 2018

RepairPal, Inc. ("RepairPal," "Company," "we," or "us") knows that you care how information about you is used and shared. This Privacy Policy explains what information of yours will be collected by RepairPal when you use RepairPal.com and related services (the “Service”), how the information will be used, and how you can control the collection, correction and/or deletion of information. We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.

## Information We Collect

User-Provided Information: You provide us information about yourself and your vehicle(s), such as your name, phone number and e-mail address, the make, model, year, mileage and repair history of your vehicle(s), when you register with the Service. If you correspond with us by email, we may retain the content of your email messages, your email address and our responses.

Tracking Technologies: We, RepairPal and our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or survey providers, use technologies such as cookies and other similar technologies to: (a) analyze trends; (b) administer the website; (c) gather demographic information about our user base as a whole; (d) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the site; (e) provide custom, personalized content and information; (f) monitor the effectiveness of our service; (g) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors and traffic; (h) diagnose or fix technology problems reported by our users or engineers that are associated with the IP addresses controlled by a specific web company or ISP; and (i) help you efficiently access your information after you sign in. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis.

Cookies Information: When you visit RepairPal.com, we may send one or more cookies - a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters - to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and lets RepairPal help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the site. A cookie does not collect personal information about you. RepairPal uses both session cookies and persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser's directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the Service may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled.

Log File Information: Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access a web page. When you register with or view our site, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information.

Clear Gifs Information: When you use the Service, we may employ clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons) which are used to track the online usage patterns of our users. No personal information from your RepairPal account is collected using these clear gifs. In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened by recipients. The information is used to enable more accurate reporting, improve the effectiveness of our marketing, and make RepairPal better for our users.

We partner with a third party to [display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites]. Our third party partner may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click [here](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

## How We Use Your Information

We use the personal information you submit to operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of the Service. Any personal information or content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Service (for instance, in Projects or other User Content you post) becomes available to the public. If you remove User Content, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other users have copied or stored your User Content.

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our website in addition to other endorsements. With your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at team@repairpal.com. By providing RepairPal your email address you consent to our using the email address to send you Service-related notices, including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail. You may opt out or change the frequency of many Service-related communications by going to the account management section of RepairPal.com. We may also use your email address to send you other messages, including changes to features of the Service and special offers. If you do not want to receive such email messages, you may opt out by sending an email message to team@repairpal.com with the word "No email" in the subject field. Opting out may prevent you from receiving email messages regarding updates, improvements, or offers. RepairPal may use certain information about you and/or your User Content without identifying you as an individual to third parties. We do this for purposes such as analyzing how the Service is used, diagnosing service or technical problems, maintaining security, and personalizing advertisements and promotions. RepairPal reserves the right, but has no obligation, to monitor the User Content you post on the site. RepairPal has the right to remove any such information or material for any reason or no reason, including without limitation, if in its sole opinion, such information or material violates, or may violate, any applicable law or our Terms of Use Agreement or to protect or defend its rights or property or those of any third party. RepairPal also reserves the right to remove information upon the request of any third party.

## How We Share Your Information

Personal Information: RepairPal will not rent or sell your personal information to others. RepairPal may share your personal information with third parties solely for the purpose of providing services to help us with our business activities such as verifying a repair occurred at a RepairPal Certified shop. If we do this, such third parties' use of your information will be bound by this Privacy Policy. These companies are also authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. We may store personal information in locations outside the direct control of RepairPal (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers). As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings. Customer, email, and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions. We may also transfer such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or dissolution. In any such transfer of information, your user information would remain subject to this Privacy Policy. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership, of uses of your personal information, and of any choices you may have regarding your personal information. In certain situations, RepairPal, Inc. may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.  
Except as otherwise described in this privacy policy, RepairPal will not disclose personal information to any third party unless required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the law, comply with legal process served on us or our affiliates, or investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities; (b) to enforce our Terms of Service, take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, or to protect the security or integrity of our site; and (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of RepairPal, our users or others. RepairPal allows other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to serve advertisements on the RepairPal site. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on RepairPal. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content. To support this interest based advertising solution, we, and companies who we have contracted with, may use information about your visits to our and other Web sites.

Although it is our hope that you find the display of advertising to you based on your interests valuable, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). You can also generally opt-out of receiving personalized ads from third party advertisers and ad networks who are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) or who follow the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising by visiting the opt-out pages on the NAI website and DAA website. Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. RepairPal does not provide any personal information to these third-party ad servers or ad networks without your consent. However, please note that if an advertiser asks RepairPal to show an advertisement to a certain audience and you respond to that advertisement, the advertiser or ad-server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers or ad networks. The RepairPal privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such advertisers.

As a customer of a RepairPal subscriber, we will not sell, rent, or lease your personal information to third parties. We may disclose your personal information to our professional advisors, contractors, business associates, related companies, and others who have agreed to treat your personal information in accordance with this privacy policy. We may share information with governmental agencies or other companies assisting us in fraud prevention or investigation. We may do so when: (1) permitted or required by law; or, (2) trying to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized transactions; or, (3) investigating fraud which has already taken place. The information is not provided to these companies for marketing purposes.

## How We Protect Your Information

RepairPal uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to RepairPal and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, RepairPal makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your email communications from RepairPal, at all times.

## Compromise of Personal Information

In the event that personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, RepairPal will promptly notify those persons whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

## Your Choices About Your Information

You may, of course, decline to submit personal information through RepairPal, in which case RepairPal may not be able to provide certain services to you. Upon request RepairPal, Inc. will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may update, correct or delete your account information and email preferences at any time by logging in to your account. You can review and correct the information about you that RepairPal keeps on file by contacting us directly at team@repairpal.com. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, and we may retain your information until you request its deletion. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. If you use a bulletin board, blog, or chat room on this Web site, you should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums. You can request the removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, by contacting us at team@repairpal.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our website, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the website. RepairPal only stores this information only long enough to send this one-time email.

## Children's Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, RepairPal does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any personal information to or on RepairPal. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at team@repairpal.com.

## Links to Other Web Sites

We are not responsible for the practices employed by Web sites linked to or from our Web site nor the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from our Web site to another Web site, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other Web site, including those that have a link on our Web site, is subject to that Web site's own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding. Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Notification Procedures

It is our policy to provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to you via email notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on our Website page, as determined by RepairPal in its sole discretion. We reserve the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to you, provided that you may opt out of certain means of notification as described in this Privacy Policy.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.

## Changes in this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact us at team@repairpal.com.

RepairPal  
363 Clementina St  
1st Floor  
San Francisco, CA 94103
